<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career on Diing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Career on Diing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:30:26 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Homelab</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:30:26 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/homelab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its been a few days since I started a simple homelab with a raspberry PI and an old laptop lying around. The first objectives of this project have been practicing networking fundamentals such as IP addresses, subnets, DNS, and security practices such as firewalls and ssh hardening. Other concepts/experiments will build on these foundations as the homelab advances into complex stages of learning cloud native technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The homelab is currently hosted on github with proper documentation of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing in a clear structured way. I believe this is a great way of learning than endless watching of tutorials on YouTube without actions. I get my hands dirty here by experimenting different approaches and analysing the &amp;ldquo;whys&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Contract</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/my-first-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:24:25 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/my-first-contract/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I crossed a major milestone, I landed my first freelance contract for a local startup NGO doing good work. They needed digital presence.&#xA;I built them a site and integrated a Content Management System that the admin can use to draft content they want to display on the website and the site builds and deploys automatically&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
